Finding aid Smith Club of Washington D.C. Records CA.MS.00320
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Washington D.C. records
1934-2008
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Washington D.C.
CA.MS.00320
4.375 linear feet (11 containers)
These records contains board meeting minutes, Smith Club of Washington, D.C.'s President's notebooks, newsletters, financial records and information on fundraisers and events, and materials concerning hosting international students in Washington D.C.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith Club of Washington D.C. is one of the oldest Smith alumnae clubs in the nation. It hosts many fundraisers and cultural events such as trips to the opera and the famous Smith Pecan Sales. The Club hosts an annual event for Smith international students allowing them to see the capital of their host country, and members volunteer at Washington D.C.'s Martin Luther King Elementary School.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains a variety of administrative and financial documents, newsletters, and the notebooks of two club presidents. The files also include materials specific to the Board of the Club and the President of the Club, publications, financial records, memorabilia including photographs, news clippings, press releases and a scrapbook. There are also files which pertain to the Club's general running, including club rosters, membership and alumnae association information.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Smith Club of Washington D.C. Records were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Related Materials
RG 90. Alumnae Association
Smith College--Alumni and alumnae--History--Sources
- Board history, 1991-99 (Box 1)
- Board of Directors, 1990-2004 (Box 1)
- Meetings of the Executive Committee (2 folders), 1959 (Box 1)
- Executive Committee Minutes, 1964-65 (Box 1)
- Executive Committee Minutes, 1966 (Box 1)
- Executive Committee Minutes, 1967 (Box 1)
- Executive Committee Minutes, 1968 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1962-64 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1969 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1977-79 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1981 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1982 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1983 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1984 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Box 2)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1987-88 (Box 2)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1989-90 (Box 2)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1994-97 (Box 2)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 1997-99 (Box 2)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 2000-03 (Box 2)
- President's Notes, 1960-61 (Box 2)
- President's Notes, 1961-62 (Box 2)
- President's Notes, 1986-89 (Box 2)
- President's Notes, 1989-90 (Box 2)
- President's Book- Section 1, 1985-86 (Box 2)
- President's Book- Section 2, 1985-86 (Box 2)
- President's Book- Section 3, 1985-86 (Box 2)
- Notebook of President (8 folders), 1968-70 (Box 3)
- Notebook of President (3 folders), 1976-77 (Box 3)
- Board Notebook (5 folders), 1956-60 (Box 3)
- Board Notebook (4 folders), 1954-64 (Box 3)
- Board Notebook (8 folders), 1964-69 (Box 4)
- Board Notebook (3 folders), 1969-71 (Box 4)
- Board Notebook (5 folders), 1971-74 (Box 4)
- Board Notebook: Lists of Board Members, minutes, agendas (12 folders), 1970s (Box 5)
- Treasurer's Records, 1970-74 (Box 5)
- Treasurer's Reports, 2000-08 (Box 5)
- Assistant Treasurer's Report, 1955-78 (Box 5)
- Assistant Treasurer's Files, 1987-88 (Box 5)
- Assistant Treasurer's Report, 1993 (Box 5)
- Tax Exemption Information, 1966; 1988 (Box 5)
- Budget, 2000-03 (Box 5)
- Analysis of Student Aid Support from Smith College Clubs, 1963-74 (Box 5)
- Scholarship Fund Account Records (3 folders), 1981 (Box 5)
- Scholarship Fund Account Records, 1999-2001 (Box 6)
- Past Benefits, 1960-66 (Box 6)
- Past Benefits, 1969-97 (Box 6)
- Past Benefits, 1998-2008 (Box 6)
- Lily Tomlin Benefit, 1988 (Box 6)
- Heidi Chronicles Benefit, 1991 (Box 6)
- Miss Saigon Benefit, 1994 (Box 6)
- Centennial Garden Party, 1995 (Box 6)
- Wit Benefit, 2000 (Box 6)
- Pecans, 1981-85 (Box 6)
- Directories (not full run), 1944-2001 (Box 7)
- Monthly Letter, 1962-64 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1951 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1952 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1960-61 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1970 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1971 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1972 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1973 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1974 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1975 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1976 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1977 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1978 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1979 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1980 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1981 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1987 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1989 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1990 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1991 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1992 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1993 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1994 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1995 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1996 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1997 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1998 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 1999 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 2000 (Box 8)
- Newsletter, 2001 (Box 9)
- Newsletter, January- May 2002 (Box 9)
- Newsletter, 2003 (Box 9)
- Newsletter, 2004 (Box 9)
- 'A Profile' - booklet about the Club, 1982 (Box 9)
- Annual Fall Forum, 1985 (Box 9)
- Annual Meetings, 1987; 1989 (Box 9)
- Annual Reports and Bylaws, 1986-89 (Box 9)
- Annual Reports, 1993-96 (Box 9)
- Alumnae Association, 1962-64 (Box 9)
- Alumnae Reception for Picker/Smithsonian Students, undated (Box 9)
- Arrangements Committee, 1960; 1967-74 (Box 9)
- Associated Alumnae Clubs, 1962-64 (Box 9)
- Associated Alumnae Clubs of Washington, 1967-76 (Box 9)
- Book and Science Awards Program, undated (Box 9)
- Bush Reception, 1981 (Box 9)
- CDO Career Services, 1993-95 (Box 9)
- CDO New Directions/Connections, 1992-95 (Box 9)
- Club Positions, undated (Box 9)
- Correspondence, 1944-99 (Box 10)
- Foreign Students Committee, 1960-61 (Box 10)
- Internship Information, 1995 (Box 10)
- Iva Dee Hiatt Memorial Concert, 1981 (Box 10)
- Mid-Atlantic Regional Symposium: Transformations in Art, Culture, and Politics at the Dawn of the 20th Century, 2002 (Box 10)
- Membership, 1985 (Box 10)
- Membership Publicity Materials, 1996 (Box 10)
- Nancy Reagan, 1981-94 (Box 10)
- National Gallery of Art, 1970 (Box 10)
- Networking Responses, 1997 (Box 10)
- Prospective Students, 1962-64; 1969 (Box 10)
- Program, 1962-64; 1991-98 (Box 10)
- Roster, 1986-87 (Box 10)
- Speech by Katherine G. Howard "Women in Politics", 1954 (Box 10)
- Smith College Founding Information, 1971 (Box 10)
- Scrapbook Clippings, 1981-94 (Box 10)
- Clippings and News Releases, 1934-2003 (Box 10)
- Photographs, 1952-2003 (Box 11)
- Scrapbook, 1981-96 (Box 11)